Nothing is more dangerous than the truth.
Official Secrets is a thriller, history, drama film directed by Gavin Hood.
The true story of British intelligence whistleblower Katharine Gun who—prior to the 2003 Iraq invasion—leaked a
top-secret NSA memo exposing a joint US-UK illegal spying operation against members of the UN Security Council.
The memo proposed blackmailing member states into voting for war.
Katharine Gun, played by Keira Knightley.
Martin Bright, played by Matt Smith.
Ben Emmerson, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Yasar Gun, played by Adam Bakri.
Peter Beaumont, played by Matthew Goode.
Ed Vulliamy, played by Rhys Ifans.
Official Secrets is a 2019 British drama film directed by Gavin Hood, based on the case of whistleblower Katharine Gun, who exposed an illegal spying operation by American and
British intelligence services to gauge sentiment of and potentially blackmail United Nations diplomats tasked to vote on a resolution regarding the 2003 invasion of Iraq.
Keira Knightley stars as Gun, alongside Matt Smith, Matthew
Goode, Adam Bakri, Indira Varma and Ralph Fiennes.
The film had its world premiere at the Sundance Film Festival on 28 January 2019 and was released in the United States
on 30 August 2019, by IFC Films, and in the United Kingdom on 18 October 2019, by Entertainment One.
The film explores themes of london, england, washington dc,
usa, politics, biography, based on true story.
The tone is emotional and intense.